#### Contact

+55 19 99176-8811 (Mobile) diogoribeiro@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/diogormendes (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Quality Assurance JavaScript Cypress

## Languages

English (Full Professional)
Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Limited Working)

#### Certifications

Certificate
Project Management Foundations
Agile Test Automation ICP-ATA
Management 3.0

Scrum Foundation Professional

Leading at a Distance

## Honors-Awards

Recognition Award

# Diogo Mendes

## Engineering

Campinas, São Paulo, Brazil

## Summary

I have more than 15 years of experience in software development projects, working from requirements analysis to customer support.

My core competencies include software development, quality assurance, DevOps, agile methodologies, and team leadership. I am passionate about empowering the team and delivering outstanding results, always focusing on client satisfaction and delivery quality. I also hold certifications in Scrum Master, Scrum Foundation, and Agile Test Automation, which demonstrate my commitment to continuous improvement and professional development.

# Experience

iFood

Engineering Manager November 2023 - Present (8 months)

Campinas, São Paulo, Brazil

I'm working on a strategic growth initiative targeting the Brazilian B and C demographics to attract and retain more users from these segments.

Leading 7 engineers composed of Android, iOS, Frontend, and Backend engineers responsible for creating dynamic gaming elements into the application to increase user engagement, traffic, and ultimately conversion rates.

My role involves overseeing the strategic direction of the project, coordinating with cross-functional teams to ensure alignment with business objectives, and providing technical guidance to the engineering team.

## Beyond

Engineering Manager January 2023 - October 2023 (10 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Working as Engineer Manager, leading 6 Engineers on two company products.

Page 1 of 8

- Signal is a Direct Booking Engine solution that provides Property managers with a full-fledged Website that helps by increasing conversion and retention.
- Tally is a state-of-the-art Payment Solution with frictionless checkout built for the Vacation Rental industry.

#### Achievements:

- Created several Monitors and Dashboards on DataDog to help the team and stakeholders to have better visibility and proactive approaches to issues
- Helped the company to move from legacy infrastructure, enabling the modernization of our products and allowing us to save money
- Continuous Improvement through Agile Methodologies
- Help facilitate feedback/recognition and career growth for the teams
- Running a continuous weekly 1:1 practice and removing blockers for your teammates
- Establishing career growth objectives and providing continuous feedback on progress for every team engineer
- Collaborating with delivery teams and external stakeholders to communicate the "why" while establishing clarity and accountability on current and future work
- Planning, managing, and allocating engineering resources based on quarterly OKRs
- Fostering an environment of technical excellence, and facilitating architectural discussions and decision-making

Scratch Financial Staff SDET Engineer October 2022 - January 2023 (4 months)

Pasadena, California, United States

- Designed and implemented a comprehensive Quality Assurance framework and continuous integration process for the entire organization
- Created and maintained numerous Cypress tests, ensuring optimal test coverage and quality assurance of code
- Enhanced end-to-end tests by incorporating new feature implementations
- Fostered team feedback, recognition, and career growth to promote employee development and job satisfaction
- Developed and streamlined an effective hiring process to attract top talent and build high-performing teams

#### Metabase

**Engineering Manager** 

February 2022 - September 2022 (8 months)

San Francisco - Remote

- Worked on migration for all CircleCI pipelines to GitHub Actions (using internal and external runners)
- Responsible for several releases (Major, Minor, Security Patches, etc...)
- Worked on creating and maintaining several Cypress tests
- Implemented new features on E2E tests
- Integrated Dashboard for Cypress analysis

#### **BEES**

**Engineering Manager** 

November 2020 - January 2022 (1 year 3 months)

Campinas, São Paulo, Brazil

Working as Engineer Manager on the Platform DevX (Developer eXperience), I've built a fully remote product and engineering team from scratch with 20 engineers to help BEES to achieve the best quality in terms of tools and processes.

Led and supported 3 teams to make the best decisions in order to help our product achieve the next level

- Continuous Improvement through Agile Methodologies
- Help the Product and Project Manager on Features x Timelines
- Help facilitate feedback/recognition and career growth for the teams
- Lead weeklies 1:1 with the team leads on their development and learning
- Act as a mediator between directors and the engineering teams
- Drive and process technical projects across the organization
- Support the establishment of a clear technical vision and roadmaps that align with business goals
- Ensure increase of engagement in the teams through health check rituals
- Collaborate across teams with other leads towards improving collaboration, performance, and value-creation
- Developed and support a hiring process and onboarding for new team members
- Improve general processes and tools for cross-team collaboration

**iFood** 

**Engineering Manager** 

January 2019 - November 2020 (1 year 11 months)

Campinas e Região, Brasil

I've built and led Mobile DevOps and Quality Assurance teams from scratch with more than 10 engineers to scale and deliver products faster and more reliably.

- Help facilitate feedback/recognition and career growth for the teams
- Lead weeklies 1:1 with the team members on their development and learning
- Collaborate across teams with other leads towards improving collaboration, performance, and value-creation
- Developed the hiring process and onboarding for new team members
- Improve general processes and tools for cross-team collaboration
- Provided technical support for the teams

### Projects:

Migration of the DevOps stack from a third-party platform to Jenkins using MacStadium and AWS (leading to 80% faster build times) using Scripted Pipelines + Shared Library + Cache strategies

Definition of flavors for Internal iFood users and also developed an in-house beta distribution for those flavors using AWS infrastructure

Use of a third-party SDK for Bug Reporting, Feature Request, Performance Analysis, and Surveys

Develop a Hybrid framework with Appium and Java for:

- Testing E2E scenarios
- Testing events
- Fallback scenarios with Mocks using Hoverfly
- Performance analysis using dumpsys
- Browserstack (Device Cloud Farm)
- STF Smartphone Test Farm (Device Local Farm)

API testing using Karate for e2e, contracts, and Performance Tests (using Gatling)

Report Portal for managing metrics and follow-ups

Restructure the QA process leading to 70% fewer Hotfixes and 85% fewer critical bugs in production

- Using X-Ray on Jira for managing and following QA numbers
- Implement BugBash on a weekly basis

Daitan Group Tech Lead January 2018 - January 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Campinas Area, Brazil

- Teach Lead of a QA / SDET Team (Manual and Automation) developing a framework/pipeline for mobile applications (iOS and Android) using Appium, Java, TestRail, Jenkins, and other tools

- Working as DevOps for creating, maintaining, and improving a GCE Cluster for a Jenkins Pipeline using Mac Minis as JNLP's
- Working as a Scrum Master for planning the roadmaps/epics with the client, planning internal sprints, and doing all the rituals.
- Using daily basis tools like Jira, Confluence, Trello, TestRail, GitHub, Xcode, Android Studio, Python, Fabric, Ansible, Fastlane

Motorola Solutions Poland SDET | Agile Lead June 2017 - December 2017 (7 months) Kraków Area, Poland

- Develop and Build a laboratory with Symantec Ghost for more than 20 computers used to run Automated Test in different windows/applications versions.
- Develop automated test cases for Motorola Subscribers (ASTRO and PCR) on C#
- Help to take the ownership and share the knowledge from a Motorola Test Framework from Plantation to Krakow
- Made a study/presentation to change the framework used to automate tests from a self-developed framework to a commercial framework in other to broaden the coverage and speed development.
- All develop / QA cycles were run in an Agile environment, including all the Scrum Rituals.
- Responsible with 2 more Krakow members to run a Scrum of Scrum meetings between all Motorola Sites.
- Attend to the 2017 EuroSTAR Automation Test Conference held in Copenhagen - Denmark

Daitan Group SDET

March 2016 - June 2017 (1 year 4 months)

Campinas Area, Brazil

- Developing a Test framework/pipeline for Mobile Application (iOS and Android) using Appium, Java, and TestRail
- Also working with tools like Jenkins, Jira, Docker, Fabric, Python and Bash

- All running on a Agile Enviriment

Sensedia

**API Consultant** 

September 2015 - March 2016 (7 months)

Campinas Area, Brazil

- Develop API for a client using Java with Spring and Maven
- API testing using Postman and SOAPUi
- Visiting the client to on a weekly basis to aling and deploy

**Thomson Reuters** 

Test Engineer

June 2015 - September 2015 (4 months)

Campinas Area, Brazil

- Responsible for testing application with all the external commerce process such as Import and Export
- Also responsible for developing tests between the application and SAP/ Oracle DB.
- Using Scrum methodology

Padtec S/A

**Test Engineer** 

April 2014 - April 2015 (1 year 1 month)

Campinas, São Paulo

As my main activity, I'm responsable to communicate with all teams and integrate all their work (web management, SW and HW) to provide PoC's of a new product.

Develop the test cases (TestLink) based on the client requirements and ratifications.

Working with OTN Switch. GMPLS, ConfD, Netconf, TestLink, Jira and Selenium

- Scrum methodology

Trópico Telecomunicações avançadas

6 years 7 months

Test Engineer

July 2011 - January 2014 (2 years 7 months)

When I was working in Trópico I was responsable for the planning, execution and validation for several telecom products like Services application, VSS and IVRs.

I also used to do regression and benchmarks test of the C/C++ applications, web network management and for the integration between Trópico and third-party partners.

In the last two years I was responsable for manage the interoperability test laboratory from Oi, Telefonica and GVT by making the direct interface between client and Trópico to provide resources, chronograms and follow-up of the approval.

#### **Test Engineer**

July 2007 - July 2011 (4 years 1 month)

- MS-Project and EPM
- · Jira, TortoiseSVN, IdeaTorrent, CACTI, Wireshark
- NGN Network / Protocols
- Operational System: Linux, Unix, Windows, DOS, MS-Office
- Cisco and 3COM routers/switches
- BladeSystem HP / IBM / PureFlex
- · Nuance ASR, Dialogic
- Software tests in C / C++ under Linux environment for telecommunications equipment
- · Preparation of scripts and bulk data for testing
- Planning and executing tests
- Approval and installation of systems in the customer network
- Responsible for trials and product integration between Trópico and third customers;
- Monitoring, analysis and recording of progress of implementation of activities;
- Approval of activities and documents related to projects

#### CPqD

Intern

January 2007 - July 2007 (7 months)

Accomplishment of performance tests, robustness and regression in products of Vectura telephony.

Instituto de Pesquisas Eldorado

Intern

July 2006 - January 2007 (7 months)

Page 7 of 8

Creation of a group for Skins tests for Motorola cellular. The group was responsible for all development of the plans of tests, and accomplishment of the same ones.

# Education

Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Campinas Electrical Engineering Technologies/Technicians · (2003 - 2007)

### **ESAMC**

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Project Manager · (2012 - 2014)